<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybersecurity on Brian Higgins Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/cybersecurity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cybersecurity on Brian Higgins Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Project: Simulated Enterprise Network</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-16/</guid>
      <description>Progress: Starting in January 2024
Outline: Beginning in January 2024, this project focuses on building a simulated enterprise network to overcome the limitations of existing cybersecurity datasets. The aim is to create a more realistic network traffic analysis environment. This simulated network will facilitate the development and testing of real-time cybersecurity models.
Key Features:
Developing a controlled simulated network for detailed analysis of network behaviour. Generating a historic traffic profile to serve as a base for experiments and model training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters Capstone: Real-Time Cyber Security Attack Detection For Network Traffic Using ML Models</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-14/</guid>
      <description>Outline: The project responded to the growing number of cyberattacks like those seen with the HSE and MTU, which pose a significant threat to individuals and organisations. It&amp;rsquo;s core objective was to strengthen IDS by integrating Machine Learning Models to focus on real-time attack detection. The research was ground breaking in its comparative analysis of different Machine Learning models using data from the Canadian Institute of Cybersecurity. The architecture leveraged baseline models and Apache Kafka for real-time data processing to deploy various ML model at threat detection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
