<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Time Series on Brian Higgins Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/time-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Time Series on Brian Higgins Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 11:13:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/time-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Time Series Data: Trends, Components, and Forecasting Models</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-11/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In this project, we aim to analyze COVID-19 time series data from a range of countries, focusing on a specific variable. We&amp;rsquo;ll start with data preparation, including cleaning and transforming the data. Then, a preliminary analysis will involve exploring data patterns, decomposing time series components, and addressing seasonality. Moving on, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into time series modeling, encompassing classical methods like exponential smoothing and advanced ARIMA modeling. This includes assessing stationarity and model selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization: Analyzing Dublin Bike Ride Data and Weather Patterns</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In this comprehensive project, Python data visualization techniques are applied to the vast and complex datasets of Dublin Bike ride data and Met Eireann weather data. The project&amp;rsquo;s core objectives encompass exploring and analyzing large datasets, harmonizing diverse datasets based on time series, and performing data cleaning using Jupyter Notebooks. Throughout the analysis, Edward Tufte&amp;rsquo;s principles for effective data presentation serve as guides, ensuring honest data representation, optimizing the data-ink ratio by eliminating non-essential elements, and providing context for more meaningful insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PH Analysis: Unravelling Manufacturing Process Variations</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In this project, I analyzed time-series bioprocessing data. I cleaned the dataset, conducted exploratory data analysis, and focused on understanding the impact of various factors on the Titre attribute. This involved summarizing batches, studying Controlling DO changes, and using statistical modeling to identify variables affecting Titre.
Programming Language: R
Topics: Core R programming topics including Data exploration and preprocessing, Time Series Analysis, Data Visualization, Feature Engineering, Descriptive Statistics, and Animated Data Visualisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
