<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Brian Higgins Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Brian Higgins Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Current Project: Final Project Of Masters of Data Science and Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-14/</guid>
      <description>Progress: This is my ongoing final project for my Masters in Data Science and Analytics with MTU. At this point I have completed tasks related to data cleaning, organization, preprocessing and exploratory data analysis. I will update later with my next stage, which is modelling.
Outline: In recent years, the threat landscape of cyberattacks has evolved, leading to an alarming increase in their complexity and impact. Notable attacks on organizations like the HSE and Munster Technology University have underlined the critical need for robust Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Disease Predication with Logistic Regression and Random Forest</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-13/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This project focuses on predicting heart disease using machine learning models, specifically Logistic Regression and Random Forest. It begins with an introduction to the significance of healthcare data in transforming the medical industry, reducing waiting times, and improving patient care. The research integrates four heart disease datasets and explores feature selection techniques to enhance model performance. Practical application development is emphasized, allowing users to input their medical data for heart disease prediction using the best-performing model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Cats and Dogs with Machine Learning and Neural Network Models</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 11:13:32 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-12/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This project aims to develop a robust image classifier that can distinguish between images of cats and dogs. The project will begin with data preprocessing, including image resizing, normalization, and label encoding. Various machine learning and neural network models, such as logistic regression, random forest, support vector machines, k-nearest neighbors, and convolutional neural networks (CNNs), will be evaluated on a smaller sample dataset. Model performance will be assessed through validation accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Time Series Data: Trends, Components, and Forecasting Models</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-11/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In this project, I aim to analyze COVID-19 time series data from a range of countries, focusing on a specific variable. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with data preparation, including cleaning and transforming the data. Then, a preliminary analysis will involve exploring data patterns, decomposing time series components, and addressing seasonality. Moving on, I&amp;rsquo;ll delve into time series modeling, encompassing classical methods like exponential smoothing and advanced ARIMA modeling. This includes assessing stationarity and model selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights into Computer-Aided Disease Detection: A Study on Kvasir-V2 Dataset</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-10/</guid>
      <description>Outline: The project involves several key components. Firstly, the dataset is split into training, validation, and test sets, laying the foundation for model development and evaluation. Challenges related to configuration and environment setup are addressed, and a baseline model is established, distinct from existing models. The architecture and purpose of each network layer are explained in plain language, and the training curves are thoroughly analyzed. Subsequently, the project explores the impact of parameter variations on model performance, such as the number of layers, filters, and nodes in fully connected layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENRON Email Spam Detection Using Various Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This project aims to develop an effective email spam detection system specifically tailored for the ENRON email dataset. The project begins with data preprocessing, where the ENRON dataset is cleaned and structured. Next, a variety of machine learning models, including but not limited to Naïve Bayes, Random Forest, and Support Vector Machines, is implemented to classify emails as spam or legitimate. Feature engineering and selection techniques are employed to optimize model performance, and a comparative analysis is conducted to evaluate the strengths and weaknesses of each model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization: Analyzing Dublin Bike Ride Data and Weather Patterns</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In this comprehensive project, Python data visualization techniques are applied to the vast and complex datasets of Dublin Bike ride data and Met Eireann weather data. The project&amp;rsquo;s core objective encompasses exploring and analyzing large datasets, harmonizing diverse datasets based on time series, and performing data cleaning using Jupyter Notebooks. Throughout the analysis, Edward Tufte&amp;rsquo;s principles for effective data presentation serve as a guide, ensuring honest data representation, optimizing the data-ink ratio by eliminating non-essential elements, and providing context for more meaningful insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiny Dashboard and Exploring Monte Carlo Simulations</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Shiny Dashboard: In this section, I developed an interactive Shiny app that facilitates data exploration and visualization of car data. The Shiny app allows users to choose any combination of two variables from the dataset and generates different types of plots based on the variable types. For numeric variables, a scatterplot is displayed. For a combination of a categorical variable and a numerical variable, a boxplot is shown. For two categorical variables, a barplot or count plot is generated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Birth Data: Implications for Maternal Healthcare </title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This project involves a comprehensive analysis of a dataset from a maternity hospital, containing information on 250 single births, with variables like birth weight, gestational weeks, maternal age, and binary indicators for low birth weight, preterm birth, hypertension, and baby gender. The main objective is to explore the connections between birth weight and these variables. The report begins with an introduction defining the research scope, followed by descriptive statistics to characterize the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PH Analysis: Unravelling Manufacturing Process Variations</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In this project, I analyzed time-series bioprocessing data. I cleaned the dataset, conducted exploratory data analysis, and focused on understanding the impact of various factors on the Titre attribute. This involved summarizing batches, studying Controlling DO changes, and using statistical modeling to identify variables affecting Titre.
Programming Language: R
Topics: Core R programming topics including Data exploration and preprocessing, Time Series Analysis, Data Visualization, Feature Engineering, Descriptive Statistics, and Animated Data Visualisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Database Exploration: SQL and MongoDB: Relational and NoSQL Databases</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Outline: Examples of the use of SQL and NoSQL queries with MongoDB to demonstrate some usage on University Courses.
Programming Language: SQL, MongoDB, Python
Topics: SQL and NoSQL commands with MongoDB
You can view different query examples here:[Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Data Analysis for Loan Approval </title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Outline: Maeve, a manager at a financial institution, contacted me and asked to determine the credit worthiness of future customers for loans. She provided 807 past loan customers with 14 attributes, such as financial standing, reason for the loan, employment, years resident in the district, etc., with a classification of each case as either good or bad loans. I performed exploratory data analysis (EDA) on the dataset, determined which attribute is the most important root node, and manually explored entropy and information using different methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BrainStation:Can Social Media Affect A Share Price? </title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This research project delves into the intriguing question: &amp;ldquo;Can social media influence a company&amp;rsquo;s share price?&amp;rdquo; The study takes GameStop, an American video game, consumer electronics, and gaming merchandise retailer, as a case study. It aims to explore whether users on social media platforms can collectively decide to buy GameStop shares, leading to significant impacts on its stock price. This question holds real-world significance, given the vast global audience on social media platforms, surpassing 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP &amp; Renewable Energy Relationship: A First Data Science Project</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In my first data science project, I delved into the potential relationship between a country&amp;rsquo;s GDP and the proportion of its energy derived from renewable sources. This study also investigated regional disparities in renewable energy trends from 1970 to 2018. Leveraging three datasets - GDP, energy consumption, and regional information - I aimed to answer key questions regarding this nexus. The outcomes provide valuable insights into the correlation between economic growth and sustainable energy adoption, while also showcasing my early venture into the realm of data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m passionate about data and problem-solving, and I’m on a journey to carve out a career in the data field. My background is a unique blend of IT expertise, adventurous travels, and a deep love for tackling complex challenges.
Before diving into data, I worked as an IT engineer on some of the largest superyachts in the world, ensuring seamless technology operations for high-profile clientele. This role honed my problem-solving skills and taught me the value of meticulous data management and organisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to reach out and connect with me through the following platforms:
Platform URL LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/brian-thomas-higgins/ GitHub: https://github.com/bhiggi01 I&amp;rsquo;m always open to networking, discussing exciting projects, or just having a chat about common interests. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to connect me on these platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
