<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Interface on Brian Higgins Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/user-interface/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User Interface on Brian Higgins Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/user-interface/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Current Project: Final Project Of Masters of Data Science and Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-14/</guid>
      <description>Progress: This is my ongoing final project for my Masters in Data Science and Analytics with MTU. At this point I have completed tasks related to data cleaning, organization, preprocessing and exploratory data analysis. I will update later with my next stage, which is modelling.
Outline: In recent years, the threat landscape of cyberattacks has evolved, leading to an alarming increase in their complexity and impact. Notable attacks on organizations like the HSE and Munster Technology University have underlined the critical need for robust Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Disease Predication with Logistic Regression and Random Forest</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-13/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This project focuses on predicting heart disease using machine learning models, specifically Logistic Regression and Random Forest. It begins with an introduction to the significance of healthcare data in transforming the medical industry, reducing waiting times, and improving patient care. The research integrates four heart disease datasets and explores feature selection techniques to enhance model performance. Practical application development is emphasized, where users can input their medical data for a heart disease prediction using the best-performing model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Cats and Dogs with Machine Learning and Neural Network Models</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 11:13:32 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-12/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This project aims to develop a robust image classifier that can distinguish between images of cats and dogs. The project will begin with data preprocessing, including image resizing, normalization, and label encoding. Various machine learning and neural network models, such as logistic regression, random forest, support vector machines, k-nearest neighbors, and convolutional neural networks (CNNs), will be evaluated on a smaller sample dataset. Model performance will be assessed through validation accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
