<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EDA on Brian Higgins Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EDA on Brian Higgins Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 11:13:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/tags/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ENRON Email Spam Detection Using Various Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>Outline: This project aims to develop an effective email spam detection system specifically tailored for the ENRON email dataset. The project will begin with data preprocessing, where the ENRON dataset will be cleaned and structured. Next, a variety of machine learning models, including but not limited to Naïve Bayes, Random Forest, and Support Vector Machines, will be implemented to classify emails as spam or legitimate. Feature engineering and selection techniques will be employed to optimize model performance, and a comparative analysis will be conducted to evaluate the strengths and weaknesses of each model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PH Analysis: Unravelling Manufacturing Process Variations</title>
      <link>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bhiggi01.github.io/Brian_Portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Outline: In this project, I analyzed time-series bioprocessing data. I cleaned the dataset, conducted exploratory data analysis, and focused on understanding the impact of various factors on the Titre attribute. This involved summarizing batches, studying Controlling DO changes, and using statistical modeling to identify variables affecting Titre.
Programming Language: R
Topics: Core R programming topics including Data exploration and preprocessing, Time Series Analysis, Data Visualization, Feature Engineering, Descriptive Statistics, and Animated Data Visualisation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
